Guide to the John Mitford, Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- OSBORN FC76
  - NORTH, GEORGE, 1710-1772
    - 2 ALS to Andrew Coltee Ducarel (1713-1785), 1724-50 (Box 1)
      1750 May 24, 1724 Aug 18
      Codicote
      5 p.; 24 x 19 cm. and 35 x 20 cm.
      Society of Antiquaries of London
      and its interests.
      76/I/9,10
  - NORTH, GEORGE, 1710-1772
    - ALS (copy) to George Vertue (1684-1756), 1751 Dec 14 (Box 1)
      6 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      Concerns a recent discovery of gold
      Saxon coins.
      76/I/11
  - NORTH, GEORGE, 1710-1772
    - Letter [copy in the hand of Andrew Coltee Ducarel (1713-1785)] to Andrew Gifford (1700-1784), 1753 Mar 28 (Box 1)
      Concerns coins belonging to the
      "late Mr. Bolton".
      76/I/12
  - NORTH, GEORGE, 1710-1772
    - ALS to Andrew Coltee Ducarel (1713-1785), 1752 Jul 6 (Box 1)
      2 p.; 32 x 21 cm.
      On business of the Society of
      Antiquaries of London.
      76/I/13
  - NORTHUMBERLAND, ALGERNON PERCY, 4TH DUKE OF, 1792-1865
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, [no yr] Aug 1 (Box 2)
      Gilbury
      Will facilitate the recipient's tour
      in Smyrna.
      76/II/134
  - NORTON, HON. MRS. CAROLINE (SHERIDAN), 1808-1877
    - 3 ALS to [John Gough Nichols (1806-1873)], [1844] (Box 1)
      9 p.; various sizes
      On the poems of William Barnes
      (1801-1886) and on a monument.
      76/I/65-67
  - PARR, SAMUEL, 1747-1825
    - ALS to Mr. Clarke, 1815 Apr 17 (Box 2)
      [Hatton]
      1 p.; 20 x 18 cm.
      Instructions for sending three
      volumes by "Todd's Flying Warwick
      Waggon".
      76/II/156
  - PEEL, SIR ROBERT, 2ND BART., 1788-1850
    - ALS to Henry Addington, 1st viscount Sidmouth (1757-1844), [1818 Jun] (Box 2)
      [Dublin]
      Sent with a memorandum (missing).
      76/II/177
  - PEGGE, SAMUEL, 1704-1796
    - ALS to John Nichols (1745-1826), 1778 (Box 1)
      1778 Jul 24-Aug 25
      Whittington and Chesterfield
      15 p.; 31 x 19 cm.
      Notes on plays in "A Select
      Collection of Old Plays" by Robert
      Dodsley (1703-1764); written on 5
      sheets posted at intervals.
      76/I/1
  - PEPYS, LADY CHARLOTTE
    - AL to Mrs. Currey, n.d. (Box 3)
      1 p.; 11 x 19 cm.
      "Lady Charlotte Pepys will enclose a
      Draft for her Account as early as
      possible".
      76/III/231
  - PETRIE, HENRY, 1768-1842
    - ALS to Gervais de la Rue, l'abbe de la Rue (1751-1835), [no yr] Sep 20 (Box 1)
      Letter of introduction by Petrie to
      the Abbot on behalf of John Mitford
      (1781-1859).
      76/I/30
  - PETRIE, HENRY, 1768-1842
    - ALS to Gervais de la Rue (l'abbe de la Rue, 1751-1835), [1817 or later] (Box 3)
      Stockwell Place
      Letter of introduction from Petrie to
      (1781-1859); also discusses their
      mutual interest in Anglo-norman
      poetry.
      76/III/233
  - PITT, WILLIAM, 1759-1806
    - Signature on an envelope, 1792 Apr 17 (Box 2)
      1 p.; 7 x 12 cm.
      76/II/91
  - POLWHELE, RICHARD, 1760-1838
    - ALS to John Bowyer Nichols (1779-1863), 1834 May 3 (Box 1)
      Polwhele
      3 p.; 20 x 12 cm.
      Death of Richard Lemon Lander
      (1804-1834) in Africa.
      76/I/43
  - POPE, ALEXANDER, 1688-1744
    - Letter (copy) to Lady Mary Wortley (Pierrepont) Montagu (1689-1762), 1720 Aug 22 (Box 2)
      Twickenham
      Wishes to buy her South Sea Stock at
      its present price.
      76/II/82
  - POPE, EDITHA, 1642-1733
    - DS: autograph MS, 1721 Nov 7 (Box 2)
      1 p.; 8 x 18 cm.
      Order for payment of South Sea Co.
      dividend to John Pope.
      76/II/90
  - PORSON, RICHARD, 1759-1808
    - Verses on [Thomas Burgess, bp. of St. Asaph (1756-1847)], [ca. 1790] (Box 2)
      2 p.; 22 x 14 cm.
      In the hand of Thomas Gaisford
      (1779-1885).
      76/II/89
  - PORSON, RICHARD, 1759-1808
    - [Formal notice of his funeral], 1808 Oct 1 (Box 3)
      1 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
      From the undertakers to Matthew
      Raine (1760-1811).
      76/III/230
  - PORTEUS, BEILBY, BP. OF LONDON, 1731-1808
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1791 Mar 31 (Box 3)
      London House
      Sermons for a proposed anthology.
      76/III/194
  - PRIOR, SIR JAMES, 1790-1869
    - 2 ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1832 (Box 1)
      1832 Jan 26, Feb 4
      Oxford Terrace, London
      On Mitford's edition of the "Life"
      of Oliver Goldsmith (1730?-1774).
      76/I/38,39
  - RICHARDSON, CHARLES, 1775-1865
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1854 Mar 12 (Box 3)
      12 Torrington Square
      3 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Etymological information.
      76/III/221
  - ROBINSON, MARY (DARBY), 1758-1800
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1788 Oct 9 (Box 3)
      3 Clarges Street
      Would like to borrow £200.
      76/III/189
  - ROGERS, SAMUEL, 1763-1855
    - ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1796 May 20 (Box 3)
      In response to a request by Knox for
      some verse; however, Rogers' Muse
      has left him.
      76/III/202
  - ROMILY, SIR SAMUEL, 1757-1818
    - ALS to J. Hanson, 1810 Feb 7 (Box 2)
      Lincolns Inn
      Wishes to know the price of
      Pontryles Estate.
      76/II/150
  - ROUTH, MARTIN JOSEPH, 1755-1854
    - 2 ALS to unidentified recipients, 1854 Aug - Dec (Box 3)
      Magdalen College, Oxford
      2 p.; 18 x 11 and 19 x 12 cm.
      [Illegible].
      With an envelope addressed to Joseph
      Lilly, Bookseller.
      76/III/228-229
  - ST. LEONARDS, EDWARD BURTENSHAW SUGDEN, BARON, 1781-1875
    - ALS to J. T. Robinson, 1834 Dec 11 (Box 2)
      Guilford [House]
      Declines an invitation.
      76/II/171
  - SCHRYVER, PETER, 1576-1660
    - ALS (in Latin) to Arnaldus Buchelius (1565-1641), 1632 May 20 (Box 1)
      Amsterdam
      2 p.; 33 x 21 cm.
      On the date of the capture of
      Damiata.
      76/I/21
  - SCOTT, SIR WALTER, BART., 1771-1832
    - "On Faulkner's Edition of Swift": autograph MS, n.d. [1808] (Box 2)
      1 p.; 21 x 16 cm.
      Verse of 14 lines discussing the
      edition of Jonathan Swift (1667-1745)
      by George Faulkner (1699-1775).
      76/II/164
  - SCOTT, SIR WALTER, BART., 1771-1832
    - ALS to [Henry Addington, 1st viscount Sidmouth (1757-1844)], 1814 May 29 (Box 2)
      [Abbotsford]
      Requests a place for an old servant.
      76/II/146
  - SHARP, RICHARD, 1759-1835
    - AL to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1786 Feb 9 (Box 3)
      Monument Hill
      Sorry he sent Clio too late to the
      house of Charles Dilly (1752-1807).
      76/III/198
  - SHARP, RICHARD, 1759-1835
    - 2 ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1821), 1795 May 29 (Box 3)
      76/III/199 responds to a call for
      aid by Knox; 76/III/200 discusses an
      epilogue for end of "Elegant
      Extracts, &c".
      76/III/199-200
  - SHERIDAN, RICHARD BRINSLEY BUTLER, 1751-1816
    - ALS to Samuel Rogers (1763-1855), [no yr] Jan 23 (Box 2)
      Saville Row (sic)
      Hopes to return a call.
      76/II/93
  - SOUTHEY, ROBERT, 1774-1843
    - 4 ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1810-27 (Box 2)
      Keswick
      8 p.; 23 x 18 cm.
      Correspondence mainly deals with
      questions of literature and Mitford's
      own writings.
      76/II/151-154
  - SPENCER, MARGARET GEORGIANA (POYNTZ), COUNTESS, 1737-1814
    - ALS to William Crowe (1745-1829), 1800 Aug 5 (Box 1)
      Bognor Rocks
      2 p.; 22 x 19 cm.
      Concerns a speech sent to her
      presumably by the recipient.
      76/I/35
  - SPENCER, PETER
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859) (Box 1)
      Ewell
      Possible descent from Edmund Spenser
      (1552-1599).
      76/I/63
  - STEEVENS, GEORGE, 1736-1800
    - ALS to Isaac Reed (1742-1807), 1787 Sep 16 (Box 2)
      Emmanuel College, Cambridge
      3 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      An invitation to Cambridge.
      76/II/118
  - STEWART, DUGALD, 1753-1828
    - ALS (fragment) to [John Stuart, 2nd marquis of Bute (1793-1848)], 1819 Nov 27 (Box 2)
      Kinneil House
      Best wishes on the recovery of the
      marquis; accompanied by a print of
      Stewart.
      76/II/162
  - STEWART, DUGALD, 1753-1828
    - ALS to Monsieur Perregaux, [no yr] Aug 11 (Box 2)
      Nimes
      1 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      Asks him to pay a jeweller on his
      behalf.
      76/II/163
  - SURREY, LADY
    - AL to [?William] Collins (1788-1847), 1841 Apr 5 (Box 1)
      Dorking
      Concerns an engraving of Lady Surrey.
      76/I/71
  - SYMMONS, CHARLES, 1749-1826
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1819 Oct 13 (Box 1)
      Chiswick
      Concerns a fair copies of a
      forthcoming work.
      76/I/36
  - TOUP, JONATHAN, 1713-1785
    - ALS to John Nourse (d.1780), 1772 Mar 6 (Box 1)
      [St. Martin's-by-Looe]
      1 p.; 29 x 20 cm.
      Concerning a printer's work on a
      76/I/22
  - TUNSTALL, JAMES, 1708-1762
    - ALS to [Zachary Grey (1688-1766)], 1742 Nov 18 (Box 2)
      1 p.; 19 x 18 cm.
      Has received writings from Henry
      Bathurst, 2nd earl Bathurst
      (1714-1794) and desires orders from
      76/II/94
  - TURNER, DAWSON, 1775-1858
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1837 Apr 17 (Box 1)
      Yarmouth
      3 p.; 25 x 20 cm.
      76/I/42
  - VOLTAIRE, FRANCOIS MARIE AROUET DE, 1694-1778
    - ALS (in French) to Bernard Louis Chauvelin, marquis de Chauvelin (1766-1832), 1762 Oct 19 (Box 2)
      4 p.; 25 x 19 cm. Discusses a play on which he is working and which he had sent to Chauvelin. "Correspondence," 9955. 76/II/100
  - WAKEFIELD, GILBERT, 1756-1801
    - 2 ALS to Vicesimus Knox (1752-1859), 1798 Nov (Box 3)
      Hackney
      5 p.; 33 x 20 and 23 x 19 cm.
      Comments on a treatise by Knox.
      76/III/212-213
  - WARBURTON, WILLIAM, BP. OF GLOUCESTER, 1698-1779
    - ALS to an unnamed recipient, 1755 Aug 11 (Box 2)
      Prior Park
      Discusses books sent and asks for
      others.
      76/II/99
  - WARTON, JOSEPH, 1722-1800
    - [Poems]: autograph MSS, n.d. (Box 3)
      11 p.; various sizes
      Collection of notes, drafts, etc.,
      of poems by Warton.
      76/III/182-186
  - WARTON, THOMAS, 1728-1790
    - ALS to George Steevens (1736-1800), 1782 Oct 23 (Box 2)
      Winchester
      Inquires as to the author of an
      attack published in a "heavy close-
      printed Pamphlet".
      76/II/113
  - WARTON, THOMAS, 1728-1790
    - ALS to Isaac Reed (1742-1807), 1789 Feb 1 (Box 2)
      Trinity College, Oxon
      1 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Requests corrections and suggestions
      for a reprint of his volume of
      Milton.
      76/II/114
  - WATTS, THOMAS, 1811-1869
    - 2 ALS to [John Mitford (1781-1859)], 1854-55 (Box 3)
      1854 Mar 13, 1855 Nov 29
      British Museum
      7 p.; 18 x 11 cm.
      Comments among other things on
      Russell's "Memoirs of Moore" and
      Boris Smith's Latin verses.
      76/III/223-224
  - WELLINGTON, ARTHUR WELLESLEY, 1ST DUKE OF, 1769-1852
    - AL to Mr. Van Stock, 1834 Nov 27 (Box 2)
      2 p.; 18 x 12 cm. with part of an
      envelope
      Declines to recommend a lady unknown
      to him.
      76/II/178
  - WELLINGTON, ARTHUR WELLESLEY, 1ST DUKE OF, 1769-1852
    - AL to Mr. Macdonald, 1836 Mar 10 (Box 2)
      76/II/179
  - WESSELING, P
    - ALS (in Dutch) to J. Plevier (Box 1)
      76/I/25
  - WILKES, JOHN, 1727-1797
    - ALS to George Colman (1732-1794), 1765 Mar 25 (Box 2)
      Naples
      Discusses his situation and state of
      mind in Naples as well as a project
      he and Colman were working upon.
      76/II/101
  - WILKES, JOHN, 1727-1797
    - Letter (copy) to the Abbe Suard, [no yr] Aug 5 (Box 2)
      King's Bench Prison
      Discusses his plans for an upcoming
      trial.
      76/II/102
  - WINDHAM, WILLIAM, 1750-1810
    - 10 ALS to Edmond Malone (1741-1812), 1793-1795 (Box 2)
      Hill Street
      13 p.; various sizes
      76/II/121-130
  - WINDHAM, WILLIAM, 1750-1810
    - ALS to Richard Brinsley Butler Sheridan (1751-1816), [1792] (Box 3)
      A plea for Hannah Brand (d. 1821).
      76/III/187
  - WORDSWORTH, CHRISTOPHER, BP. OF LINCOLN, 1807-1885
    - ALS to John Mitford (1781-1859), 1845 May 10 (Box 1)
      Leamington
      Recommends a tutor.
      76/I/64
  - WYTTENBACH, DANIEL ALBERT, 1746-1820
    - ALS (in Dutch) to an unnamed recipient, [no yr] Aug 29 (Box 1)
      1 p.; 20 x 13 cm.
      76/I/26